let me just go further to the next one
as a development practitioner how would
we communicate effectively this kind of
vision which is very different from the
car the world currently with the
stakeholders and build a shared vision
if you've had time to look at my book
you will see that in my book there are
250 questions and I think that there is
something very powerful when you shift
any kind of principle any kind of core
message that you want to engage somebody
with if you frame it as the 10
commandments or you frame it as the 10
principles of regenerative design or the
8 principles of regenerative economics
then what you ultimately asking people
to do is to jump onto your bandwagon to
follow you to say are we we've got these
10 principles and if we all follow these
principles then we will create a better
world but the minute you turn those 10
principles into questions even if
they're loaded questions that in the way
that they are phrased they guide people
to a certain way of thinking about the
problem in a certain way of acting by
putting it into a question you you take
out the energy behind this come and
follow me and just sign up and you say
your opinion matters your perspective
matters
I want to engage with you what do you
think about this and you enter into a
dialogue and I think it's that dialogue
that actually does a lot of the
transformation so the for me being a
regenerative practitioner is mastering
the art of asking questions and and
becoming very very skilled in
facilitating multi-stakeholder dialogues
that have people from all sorts of
perspectives in the room and inviting
them interests
where you bring people together around
the shared issue a shared problem like
climate change and then use that there
might be different points of view in the
room and and you invite people into
understanding that that diversity just
as in other biological systems diversity
is the core source of creativity
innovation and and and evolution so is
the diversity if we take ourselves
serious as part of life then there our
diversity and our diversity of
perspectives is also a important source
of creativity so for me what I've
experienced that sometimes what happens
when you do that people talk from their
professional roles from the academic
roles from their business roles and they
say one thing and then when you engage
with them in the in the tea break or in
between the the group conversations and
you talk to them about their children
and about what they really want out of
life and then you ask them almost the
same question suddenly they say
something completely else so there's
there's a kind of schizophrenia that
happens between people's personal truly
held emotional like embodied believes
and needs and the roles from which they
re communicate what they've learned in
their professional roles and and so very
often I find that it's it's important to
somehow take people into that deeper
space of of connecting with with their
connection to their family with the
connection to the places they really
care about and and that can can shift
the conversation